<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome | Mariel's GitHub page</title><link>https://mariel-rs.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Welcome | Mariel's GitHub page</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mariel-rs.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The path to Linux via Ubuntu MATE</title><link>https://mariel-rs.github.io/blogs/26072022_linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mariel-rs.github.io/blogs/26072022_linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>So this is me updating this blog from my Linux machine. It&amp;rsquo;s an old laptop from
around 2014 that I bought for finishing my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis. So far so good,
yet not quite the same as doing this from Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s been a fun adventure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First blog entry</title><link>https://mariel-rs.github.io/blogs/20072022_first_entry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mariel-rs.github.io/blogs/20072022_first_entry/</guid><description>&lt;p>I came across Hugo in a fortunate way in April this year. It was thanks to
the course I took with Innovaccion Virtual that I got to hear about Hugo. The
instructor, &lt;a href="https://github.com/carlogilmar">Carlo Gilmar&lt;/a>, showed us how to
create a small static website for blogging and publishing how our learning
path has been in the course.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Markdown Syntax</title><link>https://mariel-rs.github.io/sample/markdown-syntax/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mariel-rs.github.io/sample/markdown-syntax/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Emoji Support</title><link>https://mariel-rs.github.io/sample/emoji-support/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mariel-rs.github.io/sample/emoji-support/</guid><description>Emoji can be enabled in a Hugo project in a number of ways. :zap:
Emoji Support The emojify function can be called directly in templates or Inline Shortcodes.
To enable emoji globally, set enableEmoji to true in your site’s configuration and then you can type emoji shorthand codes directly in content files; e.g.
The Emoji cheat sheet is a useful reference for emoji shorthand codes.
N.B. The above steps enable Unicode Standard emoji characters and sequences in Hugo, however the rendering of these glyphs depends on the browser and the platform.</description></item><item><title>Placeholder Text</title><link>https://mariel-rs.github.io/sample/placeholder-text/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 22:41:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mariel-rs.github.io/sample/placeholder-text/</guid><description>Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de pectora summo.
Redit teque digerit hominumque toris verebor lumina non cervice subde tollit usus habet Arctonque, furores quas nec ferunt. Quoque montibus nunc caluere tempus inhospita parcite confusaque translucet patri vestro qui optatis lumine cognoscere flos nubis! Fronde ipsamque patulos Dryopen deorum.
Exierant elisi ambit vivere dedere Duce pollice Eris modo Spargitque ferrea quos palude Rursus nulli murmur; hastile inridet ut ab gravi sententia!</description></item><item><title>Rich Content</title><link>https://mariel-rs.github.io/sample/rich-content/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 19:53:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://mariel-rs.github.io/sample/rich-content/</guid><description>Hugo ships with several Built-in Shortcodes for rich content, along with a Privacy Config and a set of Simple Shortcodes that enable static and no-JS versions of various social media embeds.
Gist Simple Shortcode {{&amp;lt; gist spf13 7896402 &amp;#34;img.html&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} Twitter Simple Shortcode {{&amp;lt; tweet GoHugoIO 1315233626070503424 &amp;gt;}} Profile is a customizable single-page portfolio theme for Hugo featuring a contact form and blog. Made by @gurusabarishh.https://t.co/KwYcwfdy16
&amp;mdash; GoHugo.io (@GoHugoIO) October 11, 2020 Vimeo Simple Shortcode {{&amp;lt; vimeo 146022717 &amp;gt;}} Youtube Simple Shortcode {{&amp;lt; youtube w7Ft2ymGmfc &amp;gt;}}</description></item></channel></rss>